DEEPTI DHUMAVAT

MOBILE, SERVER & WEB DEVELOPER

Profile

- Around 9 years of core IT experience in design, development and support of mobile, server and web applications. Around 5.6+
 years of iOS mobile development and 3+ years of server and web development.
- · Currently working as Team Lead with Persistent Systems Limited.
- · Passionate about building useful, beautiful applications

Skills

Languages: iOS(Objective-c), Swift, Angular2 - Native script, Typescript, Reactive Programming, Core Java/J2EE, Adobe Flex, Action script

Databases: MySQL, Sqlite, Core Data

Development Software: Git, Perforce, Svn, Xcode, Eclipse, Netbeans, Adobe Flex Builder

Experience

SmartIT

Team Lead / Module Lead / Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer (Persistent Systems March 2015- present)

Technologies: iOS (Objective-C), Swift, Core Data, Fastlane

Used by users in companies to increase productivity when managing service tickets. Highlights include creating and viewing rich-media knowledge articles, scanning and managing assets, and a smart recorder that provides real-time relevant data to the agent as they are creating new tickets

Innovation Suite

Module Lead iOS Mobile Developer (Persistent Systems 2016- December 2017) Technologies: Swift, Reactive Swift, NativeScript

Innovation Suite platform using NativeScript and the latest version of Angular.Innovation Suite targets developers who want to extend functionality by creating reusable mobile components and Business Analysts that want to develop code-less mobile applications.

Resigning & Rebranding Utility

Module Lead iOS Mobile Developer (Persistent Systems September 2016- present) Technologies : Cocoa (Objective-C)

This is Mac desktop application which allows users to sign/resign the .ipa and the .xcarchives files with their own Developer account for Enterprise/In-house /App store distribution for preconfigured applications. We can configure multiple applications by just adding few configurations and then distribute to the customers via utility so that they can create their own resigning project using the templates provided for preconfigured applications and their versions and fill in necessary details and resign it. Users can also rebrand the application by providing their own app icons, custom images, App colors they plan to replace in the existing application while re-

signing.

Education

- Master Computer Science, Modern College Shivajinagar, Pune University, Post Graduated 2009 - Higher Second Class
- Bachelor Computer Science, Nowrosjee Wadia College, Pune University, Graduated 2007 - Distinction

CONTACT

deepti.dhumavat@gmail.com

8055224956, 8237443556

B4/20, Kumar Angan Society, Opp. to Neeta Park Society, Airport road, Yerwada Pune-411006

Mobiliya Manage

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer (AgreeYa Mobility December 2014 - February 2015)

Technologies : iOS (Objective-C)

Mobiliya Manage is an In-House Device Management - MDM client which is installed once the user is on boarded through MDM Server. It is used to enforce policies and constraints on device such as Geofencing through and time based policies by monitoring users current Geofence. Once user enters a particular Geofence the server is updated with the state active/inactive for policy and then server pushes MDM restrictions and policies as defined.

Onvelop

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer (AgreeYa Mobility April 2014 - November 2015) Technologies : iOS (Objective-C), Core Data, Box Apis

Onvelop is a mobile communication and collaboration tool used to:

- . Manage, Share and Edit SharePoint documents from mobile devices
- · Navigate SharePoint sub sites
- · Instant Messaging Chat (Lync), peer-to-peer o VoIP Audio Call (Lync), peer-to-peer o Video Call (Lync), peer-to-peer

- · Access SharePoint/personal calendar, tasks and manage teams using your mobile device
- · Access to all SharePoint default lists discussion boards, wiki etc.
- . Exchange Email client.
- . Access to Dropbox, Sky drive, Box documents upload and download.

Lighthouse

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer (AgreeYa Mobility January 2014 - April 2014) Technologies: iOS (Objective-C), Core Data, Json Apis

Lighthouse is a Mobile Device Management Application, which can be used to manage devices remotely. Once installed, the user is subject to policies enforced by the application. App executes jobs coming from the server they are of type Execute Alarm; Get Device Information, Get Location Information, Update Refresh Policies etc.

RIO

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer (Mobimedia Technologies May 2013 - December 2013)

Technologies: PHP, MySQL, Magento, Java, Web services, iOS (Objective-C), Core Data, Json Apis, Localization Support, Google Maps Api, Saudi Post Apis

Rio is marketplace that offers various services like Quick Service Restaurants, Groceries, and Travel etc. to consumers on their mobile phones. Consumers discover a wide variety of products through RIO services. They signup, browse catalog, place order, track order, earn loyalty points and much more. Various secured payment options like cash on delivery, credit/debit cards, loyalty point redemption payments, net banking etc. are available. The app communicates with highly scalable RIO platform that brings customers and retailers together at one place. Website Link: www.rioquest.com

App Link: https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/rioquest/id804745449?mt=8

mGenie

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer

Technologies: iOS (Objective-C) QUALCOMM's Vuforia sdk, NFC Reader Apis, Sqlite

mGenie is an Augmented Reality based consumer interaction and engagement solution. It brings traditional media campaigns (poster, newspaper adverts, Web adverts, Billboards) alive through simple actions like- Consumers tap or Scan Images, Logos, and QR Codes etc to interact with brands and bring adverts to life through Goto URL, Play Audio, Video, Save vCard, View in 3D, etc. History of scans helps consumers access the advert again at any time. Campaign effectiveness can be measured to track and analyse consumer actions (date, time, action taken, location, etc).

Mil ife

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer

Technologies: Java, Hibernate, JMS (HornetQ), Restful Web-services, MySql, Jboss

MiLife is SOA for providing different services to mobile clients. It provides various services such as couponing service i.e. running different campaigns of brands, redemption service, loyalty service ,stocks alert service, push notifications service, payment service etc which can be consumed by the mobile MiLife wallet app. Consumers can see offers on their phones using the wallet app and can action these coupons save forward, redeem, refer, buy, share etc.

Nerdit

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer Technologies: iOS (Objective-C), Core Data, Twitter Apis

Nerdit is the act of sharing /seeking knowledge through Twitter. The app is designed to produce the most powerful instructional tweets possible. Each nerdit! Instructional tweet includes a simple rule of thumb and is punctuated with an emotion. The resulting sound bite of knowledge is easily incorporated in the thoughts of those receiving your nerdit!, and can be delivered in 140 characters or less. People can seek advice as well as share advice using the nerdit! Formula .Tag each instructional Tweet with the name of your social learning group. Save your #ShortInstructionalMessages for future delivery in Pending Advice.

Link: http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/nerdit/id544003466?mt=8

PaidPunch

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer Technologies: iOS (Objective-C), Core Data, Facebook Apis, Json Apis

Business sell prepaid digital vouchers of store credit (punches) to consumers. Consumers can buy these digital vouchers through credit cards using the app. It also helps consumers to share their activities of winning prizes etc on facebook and also login using facebook accounts. Every time you purchase Punches, you get a FREE Mystery Punch, which will make consumers win mystery prizes. It keeps track of your paid punch cards, punches used and remaining punches .The PaidPunch app makes it easy to:

- Save money on every visit
- Earn prizes
- Discover new places to go and things to do in your city

Link: http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/paidpunch/id501977872?mt=8

mCoupons/ mEngage

Senior Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer

Technologies: iOS (Objective-C), Core Data, Facebook Apis, Xml, Push Notifications, Zxing API, Flurry Analytics

mCoupons application provides consumers to receive rich branded coupons in their mcoupon wallet on their phones. Mcoupon is an actionable discount coupon delivered to consumers on their mobile phones. Consumers can action these coupons save forward, redeem, refer, and share. Consumers can view an offer get a coupon and then take actions on it. It also provides store locator functionality for an offer. It also handles remote push notifications for new coupons.

mLoyalty

Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer

Technologies: iOS (Objective-C), Core Data, Facebook Apis, Push Notifications, Zxing API, Phone Monkey

mLoyalty is a loyalty based application wherein consumers can have their loyalty card on their phone. Loyalty card can have coupons associated, which can be redeemed. It also has store locator, share and check in functionality and also handles push notifications for new coupons.

FakeBuster

Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer

Technologies: Java, Hibernate, Soap Web services, MySQL, Adobe Flex (Action script), Android, SQLite

Fake Buster application is product authenticity verification application combined with track and trace. It is used to check genuineness of the products. It Helps brands to generate secure codes for product items and based on rules assigned it identifies fake and genuineness of products.

Aircodez

Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer Technologies: iOS (Objective-C), Sqlite-3, Zxing API

Aircodez is a QR Code Scanner application that allows auto scanning of QR code using a camera on your mobile device. QrCodes can be used to access web links, download content, add contacts, initiate a call or send sms. Additionally the Aircodez mobile app also retains the information of the QR Codes you have scanned earlier and allows you to access that information at any time. Consumers can scan any QR Code they see in adverts and get back more information and actions setup by brands related to the advertisements.

Link: http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/aircodez/id473997014?mt=8

QR Code Campaign Manager

Software Engineer iOS Mobile Developer Technologies: Jsp (Servlets), Adobe Flex (Action script), MySQL

The QR Code Campaign Manager helps brands create QR Code based campaigns, by encoding campaign information into a QR Code or 2-D bar code. These bar codes created in different sizes can then be used in advertisements in various media (TV, Airport Banners, Print Ads, etc). The Campaign Manager keeps track of the phone numbers of mobile devices that scanned QR Codes and took actions on the additional information setup by the brand. Brands get detailed reports of QR Codes scanned, actions taken by consumers, etc.

Work Chronology

- Team Lead / Module Lead / Senior Software Engineer (iOS), Persistent Systems Limited (2015 - Present)
- Senior Software Engineer (iOS), AgreeYa Mobility (2014 -2015)
- Senior Software Engineer / Software Engineer (iOS, Java/J2EE Server, Flex), Mobimedia Technologies Pvt. Ltd (2011 - 2013)
- Software Engineer / Intern (Flex, Java/J2EE Server), iStream Technologies Pvt. Ltd (2009 -2011)